# Naman Madharia

Pune, Maharashtra, India 🛮 naman.madharia@outlook.com 🛘 +91 9009682829 🛅 linkedin.com/in/naman-madharia

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that accelerate the effectiveness and efficiency of organisational success. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create reliable and user-friendly systems. A confident communicator, strategic thinker and innovative creator to develop software that is tailored to meet the company's organisational needs.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Data Virtualization Engineer**

## **TIBCO Software**

February 2023 - Present, Pune, Maharashtra, India · On-site

- · Skills: PostgreSQL · Databases · Java · TDV · Linux.
- · Developed and maintained complex SQL scripts and procedures.
- · Implementing all to efficiently extract, transform, and load data from sources into TDV, ensuring high data quality and performance.

#### Software Engineer I

#### **Parkar Digital**

October 2021 - January 2023, Pune, Maharashtra, India · Hybrid

- Skills: Docker Swarm Git Docker Linux Docker compose Java.
- $\cdot \ Engaged \ with \ Science Logic's \ Powerflow \ team \ to \ develop \ core \ Platform, REST \ APIs \ and \ external \ plugin \ integrations \ using \ Java.$
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Develop three critical software programs for monitoring, tracking, event creating and reporting with better performance.}$

### **Project Intern**

CDAC

January 2021 - July 2021, Pune, Maharashtra, India

- · Skills: Linux, Java, SLURM and HPC.
- · Developed using Java and SLURM, the required utilities for the project which can consume shared resource pool.
- · Using Simple LINUX Utility Resource Management SLURM to maximize the performance of IO and processing of jobs.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science

MIT Academy of Engineering, Alandi, Pune · 2021

#### **SKILLS**

Frontend and Backend: React JS and JavaScript, Java, Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate and JVM.

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL and MongoDB.

Other: Windows, Linux, Docker, Docker Swarm, Jenkins, Data Structures and Algorithms.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

# CodeChef Certified Data Structures and Algorithms Programme

CodeChef · 2021

# TCA-TIBCO Data Virtualization Associate

TIBCO · 2023

#### Microsoft certified: Azure Fundamentals

Microsoft · 2022

### **PROJECTS**

#### Data Analyzer

June 2023 - Present

- · Data Analyzer- Java-based data analysis tool designed to handle and process large volumes of data from various input sources.
- · This versatile application empowers users to gain valuable insights from their data through a range of analytical techniques.
- This helps to extract meaningful info even if one hold structured data in DB, unstructured text in documents, or log files from applications.

# **Burst Buffer**

CDAC · January 2021 - July 2021

• Burst Buffer bridges the performance gap between the processing speed of the compute nodes and the I/O bandwidth of the storage systems.